<idea-plugin version="2">
    <name>Gradle View</name>
    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>What is this?</b></p>
        <p>Show a split tree rollup of the dependencies for each Gradle configuration in use by a project.</p>

        <p><b>Why would I need this?</b></p>
        <p>
            Dependency wrangling isn't easy in a large Java project. This IntelliJ IDEA plugin was built to add a little
            more sanity to the tedious task of analyzing dependencies by rolling up the entire dependency graph into a
            pair of more easily digestible trees derived from a serialized version of Gradle's dependency graph. The
            Dependency List provides a lexicographically sorted set of all the dependencies for each configuration in
            your project and all of its sub-projects. The Dependency Hierarchy shows a nested view of each Gradle
            configuration in your project and all of its sub-projects. Grey dependencies in the tree indicate it was
            included by a previous dependency that was added before (and can be safely omitted if it is explicitly
            being included).
        </p>

        <p><b>Features</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Built on the Gradle Tooling API 5.6.2, but should work on other recent versions</li>
            <li>Visual highlighting to indicate dependencies in use and replacement versions</li>
            <li>Lexicographically sorted listing for all Gradle configurations</li>
            <li>Load any project's Gradle dependencies, not just the one currently open inside IntelliJ</li>
            <li>Toggle the showing of replaced dependencies</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>
    <version>4.0.0</version>
    <change-notes><![CDATA[
    <p>4.0.0 - 2019-11-20
    <ul>
        <li>Upgrade internal tooling API to use Gradle 5.6.2 which adds Java 11 support</li>
        <li>Gradle wrapper is now at Gradle 5.6.2</li>
        <li>Java bytecode compatibility bumped up to 1.8 to support later versions of Gradle Tooling API</li>
        <li>Switch to using the org.jetbrains.intellij plugin for more modern plugin development</li>
        <li>Removed old gradle-one-jar plugin in favor of shadow</li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>3.0.0 - 2017-11-21
    <ul>
        <li>Upgrade internal tooling API to use Gradle 3.5.1</li>
        <li>Add dependency resolution compatibility fixes to support Gradle 2.x, 3.x, and 4.x</li>
        <li>Java bytecode compatibility bumped up to 1.7 to support later versions of Gradle Tooling API</li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>2.1.0 - 2015-04-27
    <ul>
        <li>Upgrade internal tooling API to use Gradle 2.3 <a href="https://github.com/rholder/gradle-view/issues/11">#11</a></li>
        <li>Removed painful light red on blue background selection color <a href="https://github.com/rholder/gradle-view/issues/6">#6</a></li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>2.0.2 - 2014-10-06
    <ul>
        <li>Fixed some wonky Windows JAVA_HOME path behavior <a href="https://github.com/rholder/gradle-view/issues/5">#5</a></li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>2.0.1 - 2014-09-22
    <ul>
        <li>Fixed a Windows path bug with absolute file names <a href="https://github.com/rholder/gradle-view/issues/5">#5</a></li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>2.0.0 - 2014-09-10
    <ul>
        <li>Major rewrite of the Gradle Tooling API integration using 1.12 and custom model serialization</li>
        <li>Added handling of multi-module project dependency graphs for all configurations</li>
        <li>Added separate scrolling log window</li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>1.0.1 - 2013-07-21
    <ul>
        <li>Adjusted color for highlighting on the Darcula theme</li>
        <li>Added toggle to switch between display of actual/replaced versions for <a href="https://github.com/rholder/gradle-view/issues/3">#3</a></li>
        <li>Fixed handling of configurations with "No dependencies" for <a href="https://github.com/rholder/gradle-view/issues/2">#2</a></li>
        <li>Code cleanup and preparation for the dependencyInsight task once it's available in the Gradle Tooling API</li>
    </ul>
    </p>

    <p>1.0.0 - 2012-01-03
    <ul>
        <li>Initial stable release</li>
    </ul>
    </p>
    ]]></change-notes>
    <vendor>rholder</vendor>

    <idea-version since-build="135"/>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.lang</depends>

    <application-components>
    </application-components>

    <project-components>
        <component>
            <implementation-class>com.github.rholder.gradle.intellij.GradleService</implementation-class>
        </component>
    </project-components>

    <actions>
        <group id="GradleView.NavigatorActionsToolbar">
            <action id="GradleView.Refresh"
                    class="com.github.rholder.gradle.intellij.RefreshTreeAction"
                    text="Refresh"
                    description="Refresh the Gradle view"
                    icon="/actions/sync.png"/>
            <action id="GradleView.Reset"
                    class="com.github.rholder.gradle.intellij.ResetTreeAction"
                    text="Load"
                    description="Load the Gradle view from another project"
                    icon="/actions/menu-open.png"/>
            <action id="GradleView.ToggleShowReplace"
                    class="com.github.rholder.gradle.intellij.ToggleShowReplacedAction"
                    text="Show/Hide Replaced Dependencies"
                    description="Show or hide replaced dependencies"
                    icon="/toolbar/filterdups.png"/>
        </group>

    </actions>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow id="Gradle View" anchor="bottom" factoryClass="com.github.rholder.gradle.intellij.GradleViewToolWindowFactory" icon="/general/add.png"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
